Henry F. Dobyns Papers 1732-2009 (bulk 1950-2000)
University of Arizona Libraries, Special Collections
- Series VII: Activity Files, 1947-2001
  - Subseries 1: American Society for Ethnohistory, 1962-2001
    - Officer lists, 1968 (Box 215, Folder 17)
    - Reprint requests, 1967-1968 (Box 215, Folder 18)
    - Reprint requests, 1969-1970 (Box 215, Folder 19)
    - Research Foundation of State University of New York, 1967-1968 (Box 215, Folder 20)
    - Steering committee on publications, 1977 (Box 215, Folder 21)
    - Student membership drive, 1970 (Box 215, Folder 22)
    - Subscription requests, 1962-1966 (Box 215, Folder 23-24)
    - Subscription requests, 1967 (Box 215, Folder 25-26)
    - Subscription requests, 1967 (Box 216, Folder 1-3)
    - Subscription requests, 1968 (Box 216, Folder 4-5)
    - Subscription requests, 1969 (Box 216, Folder 6-10)
    - Subscription requests, 1970 (Box 216, Folder 11-12)
    - Subscription requests, 1970 (Box 217, Folder 1-2)
    - University of Buffalo Foundation, 1967-1968 (Box 217, Folder 3)
    - University of Kentucky Research Foundation, 1968-1970 (Box 217, Folder 4)
  - Subseries 2: Anza Trail, 2008-2009
    This subseries contains manuscripts, maps and research material related to the National Park Service Anza Trail project.
    - Budget, 2008-2009
    - Contacts, 2008-2009
    - Correspondence, 2009
    - Interview Data, 2009
    - Manuscripts, 2008-2009
    - Maps, 2009
    - Meetings, 2008-2009
    - Photographs, 2009
    - Quarterly reports, 2008-2009
    - Research material, 2008-2009
  - Subseries 3: Casa Grande Valley Historical Society, 1975-2002
    This subseries contains contains correspondence, writings and research materials related to work as a consultant. Boxes 217-218.
    - Benedict, Kay, 1976-2002 (Box 217, Folder 5-6)
    - Casa Grande Municipal Government, 1977 (Box 217, Folder 7)
    - Casa Grande Woman’s Club Biographical Sketches, 1976 (Box 217, Folder 8)
    - The Casa Grande Woman’s Club Mother of Institutions, 1976 (Box 217, Folder 9)
    - A Comparison of Social and Material Changes among Inhabitants of the Middle Gila River Valley, Arizona, 1978 (Box 217, Folder 10)
    - Correspondence A-V, 1976-1993 (Box 217, Folder 11)
    - Editorial Board, 1975-1994 (Box 217, Folder 12)
    - Flexible Farmers, undated (Box 217, Folder 13)
    - Optimists in a Desert “Paradise”, 1976 (Box 217, Folder 14)
    - Outlines, undated (Box 217, Folder 15)
    - Research materials, undated (Box 217, Folder 16-21)
    - Research materials, undated (Box 218, Folder 1)
    - Trails conference speech, undated (Box 218, Folder 2)
    - Unidentified manuscript, undated (Box 218, Folder 3)
    - The United Presbyterian Church of Casa Grande, 1976 (Box 218, Folder 4)
    - University of Florida Ethnology Seminar, 1978 (Box 218, Folder 5)
    - Weik, Shirley, 1977-1978 (Box 218, Folder 6)
  - Subseries 4: Conferences, 1947-2000
    This subseries contains programs, speeches and papers related to conferences attended. Boxes 218-219.
    - Across Generations Symposium, 1973 (Box 218, Folder 7)
    - American Anthropological Association annual meeting, 1982 (Box 218, Folder 8)
    - American Association for the Advancement of Science, 1956, 1992 (Box 218, Folder 9)
    - American Association for the Advancement of Science- Drinking Patterns in Latin America, 1965-1970 (Box 218, Folder 10-13)
    - American Indian Population History, 1200-1900, 1990 (Box 218, Folder 14)
    - Anthropology and Indian Land Claims Litigation, 1955 (Box 218, Folder 15)
    - Central States Anthropological Society annual meeting, 1983 (Box 218, Folder 16)
    - Community Development Seminar, 1967 (Box 218, Folder 17)
    - Conference on Human Relations, 1950 (Box 218, Folder 18)
    - Disease and Demography in the Americas, 1989 (Box 218, Folder 19)
    - International Congress of Americanists, 1970 (Box 218, Folder 20)
    - National Endowment for the Humanities Conference on the Colombian Quincentenary, 1984 (Box 218, Folder 21)
    - National Symposium on American Indian Research, 1981 (Box 218, Folder 22)
    - Native American Community Libraries: Workshop II, 1981 (Box 218, Folder 23)
    - Native American Cultural Awareness workshop, 1993 (Box 218, Folder 24)
    - Practical Approaches to Riparian Management: An Educational Workshop, 1989 (Box 219, Folder 1)
    - Programs, 1949-1969 (Box 219, Folder 2)
    - Programs, 1970-2000 (Box 219, Folder 3)
    - Rethinking the Encounter, 1988 (Box 219, Folder 4)
    - Society for Applied Anthropology, 1957-1979 (Box 219, Folder 5)
    - Southeastern Indians, 1987 (Box 219, Folder 6)
    - Southwest Symposium, 1988-1989 (Box 219, Folder 7-8)
    - Spanish Pathways in Florida, 1988-1990 (Box 219, Folder 9)
    - University of Arizona Conference for Field Workers, 1947 (Box 219, Folder 10)
    - University of Texas-Arlington lecture- Native American Demography, 1988 (Box 219, Folder 11)
    - Western History Association, 1980-1982 (Box 219, Folder 12-13)
    - World History Association, 1992 (Box 219, Folder 14)
  - Subseries 5: Cultural Systems Research Inc., 1978
    This subseries contains correspondence, research and interviews related to work as a consultant. Boxes 219-220.
    - Attitude analysis, 1978 (Box 219, Folder 15)
    - Background materials, 1978 (Box 219, Folder 16)
    - Bell, Fillman, 1978 (Box 219, Folder 17)
    - Chemehuevi, 1978 (Box 219, Folder 18)
    - Cocopah, 1978 (Box 219, Folder 19)
    - Correspondence A-Y, 1978 (Box 219, Folder 20)
    - Depth interviews, 1978 (Box 219, Folder 21)
    - Equipment rentals, 1978 (Box 219, Folder 22)
    - Interviews in Phoenix urban area of Native Americans, 1978 (Box 219, Folder 23)
    - Interviews in Prescott urban area, 1978 (Box 219, Folder 24)
    - Interviews in rural Arizona of Native Americans, 1978 (Box 220, Folder 1)
    - Interviews in rural Arizona of Native American- Yavapai, 1978 (Box 220, Folder 2)
    - John, Jane, 1978 (Box 220, Folder 3)
    - Lowell, John, 1978 (Box 220, Folder 4)
    - Maricopa analysis, 1978 (Box 220, Folder 5)
    - Northeastern Pai analysis, 1978 (Box 220, Folder 6)
    - Northern Pimas analysis, 1978 (Box 220, Folder 7)
    - Receipts, 1978 (Box 220, Folder 8)
    - Report, 1978 (Box 220, Folder 9)
    - Research materials, 1978 (Box 220, Folder 10)
    - Theory chapter, 1978 (Box 220, Folder 11)
    - Urban Prescott/Phoenix, 1978 (Box 220, Folder 12)
    - Vane, Sylvia, 1978 (Box 220, Folder 13)
    - Yavapai analysis, 1978 (Box 220, Folder 14)
  - Subseries 6: Organization of American States, 1975-1976
    This subseries contains material related to research in Latin America including reports produced and a class attended. Box 221.
    - Bibliography and research, 1975-1976 (Box 220, Folder 15-16)
    - Contracts, 1975-1976 (Box 220, Folder 17)
    - Correspondence B-U, 1976 (Box 220, Folder 18)
    - Inventories, 1976 (Box 220, Folder 19)
    - Notes, 1976 (Box 220, Folder 20)
    - Post graduate course, 1975-1976 (Box 220, Folder 21-24)
    - Report- La Carretera Antioqueña al Mar, 1976 (Box 220, Folder 25)
    - Reports- Proyecto Darien, 1976 (Box 221, Folder 1)
  - Subseries 7: Piñon Press, 1977-1986
    This subseries contains financial statements, book orders and correspondence related to the ownership of a book publishing company. Box 221.
    - Bank statements, 1982-1983 (Box 221, Folder 2)
    - Book orders, 1977-1983 (Box 221, Folder 3)
    - Bradfield, Stillman, 1978 (Box 221, Folder 4)
    - Copyright forms, 1977-1980 (Box 221, Folder 5)
    - Correspondence A-N, 1977-1979 (Box 221, Folder 6)
    - Euler, Robert, 1977-1979 (Box 221, Folder 7)
    - Expenses, 1979-1981 (Box 221, Folder 8)
    - Jones, Kristine, 1978-1979 (Box 221, Folder 9)
    - The Navajo People orders, 1982 (Box 221, Folder 10)
    - Notes, undated (Box 221, Folder 11)
    - Press share purchase, 1978 (Box 221, Folder 12)
    - Receipts, 1979-1983 (Box 221, Folder 13)
    - Stoffle, Richard, 1977-1978 (Box 221, Folder 14)
    - Weiner, Melissa Ruffner, 1978-1986 (Box 221, Folder 15)
    - Weiner, Melissa Ruffner- Expenses, 1980-1983 (Box 221, Folder 16)
    - Weiner, Melissa Ruffner- Water in a Thirsty Land, 1978 (Box 221, Folder 17)
  - Subseries 8: Tohono O’odham Nation Files, 1937-1977
    This subseries correspondence, tribal council minutes and research materials related to claims research for the Tohono O’odham. Box 221.
    - Association for Papago Affairs, 1954-1956 (Box 221, Folder 18)
    - Bibliography, 1950 (Box 221, Folder 19)
    - Claims research preservation, 1954 (Box 221, Folder 20)
    - Correspondence A-T, 1950-1958 (Box 221, Folder 21)
    - Council meetings, 1937-1957 (Box 221, Folder 22)
    - Handbook, 1951 (Box 221, Folder 23)
    - Language, 1950 (Box 221, Folder 24)
    - Manuel, Mark, 1954-1957 (Box 221, Folder 25)
    - Rodeo, undated (Box 221, Folder 26)
    - Student reports, 1949 (Box 221, Folder 27)
    - Tribal Organization, 1949 (Box 221, Folder 28)
    - Water rights, 1976-1977 (Box 221, Folder 29)
- Series VIII: Hualapai Tribal Nation Files, 1897-1986
  This series contains material related to Dobyns’ time as an expert witness for the Hualapai Tribe on a land claims case including manuscripts used in the legal cases, correspondence, court documents and research material. This series is arranged alphabetically. This series contains restrictions on material in box 221 folder 30-37, box 222 and box 223.
  - Restricted (Box 221, Folder 30)
  - Restricted (Box 221, Folder 31)
  - Restricted (Box 221, Folder 32)
  - Restricted (Box 221, Folder 33)
  - Restricted (Box 221, Folder 34)
  - Restricted (Box 221, Folder 35)
  - Restricted (Box 221, Folder 36)
  - Restricted (Box 221, Folder 37)
  - Restricted (Box 222)
  - Restricted (Box 223)
- Series IX: Research Files, 1947-2009
  This series includes research material related to Dobyns’ work including research notes and field notebooks. This series is arranged alphabetically. This series contains restrictions on material in box 226, box 227 folder 1 and 228 folder 1.
  - Anthropology department evaluation data, 1977 (Box 224, Folder 1-5)
  - Anza trail, 2008-2009 (Box 224, Folder 6)
  - Archivo General de la Nacion, undated (Box 224, Folder 7-8)
  - Archivo del Gubierno de la Mitra de Sonora, undated (Box 224, Folder 9)
  - Archivo Historico del Estado de Sonora, undated (Box 224, Folder 10)
  - Arizona Battles, 1992 (Box 224, Folder 11)
  - Arizona Historical Society photographs index, undated (Box 224, Folder 12-13)
  - Arizona Historical Society photographs index, undated (Box 225, Folder 1-2)
  - Arizona Historical Society photographs- Gila-Salt River Watershed Streams, 2003 (Box 225, Folder 3)
  - Benson, Arizona, undated (Box 225, Folder 4)
  - Comaduran, Antonio, undated (Box 225, Folder 5)
  - Desertification Dynamics in the Sonoran Desert, 1540-1900, 1977 (Box 225, Folder 6)
  - Diet surveys, undated (Box 225, Folder 7-11)
  - Drinking patterns, 1967 (Box 225, Folder 12)
  - Echeagaray, Manuel, undated (Box 225, Folder 13)
  - Energy Fuels Nuclear, Inc., 1986 (Box 225, Folder 14)
  - Ethnohistory authors, 1994 (Box 225, Folder 15)
  - Ezell- Celaya interview, 1952 (Box 225, Folder 16)
  - Festivals, undated (Box 225, Folder 17)
  - Restricted (Box 226)
  - Restricted (Box 227, Folder 1-7)
  - Figueroa- Colorado River expedition, undated (Box 227, Folder 8)
  - First Drop or Last documents, 1990 (Box 227, Folder 9)
  - Fort Grant, undated (Box 227, Folder 10)
  - Garces, Francisco, undated (Box 227, Folder 11)
  - Gila River Pimas 1849 Trade, undated (Box 227, Folder 12)
  - Gileño documents, undated (Box 227, Folder 13-15)
  - Hopi population trends, undated (Box 227, Folder 16)
  - Restricted (Box 228, Folder 1)
  - Indian Tribal Series, 1973-1974 (Box 228, Folder 2)
  - Iroquois, 1979 (Box 228, Folder 3)
  - Ivory Merry go Round, 1966-1978 (Box 228, Folder 4)
  - Journal of Arizona History authors, 1994 (Box 228, Folder 5)
  - Lipan Apache, 1954-1955 (Box 228, Folder 6-7)
  - Magdalena de Kino Festival, undated (Box 228, Folder 8)
  - Magdalena, Sonora Parish history, undated (Box 228, Folder 9)
  - Maize processing, undated (Box 228, Folder 10)
  - Maps, undated (Box 228, Folder 11)
  - Microfilm synopses, undated (Box 228, Folder 12)
  - News clippings- Argentina, 1963-1965 (Box 228, Folder 13)
  - News clippings- Arid lands and water use, 1965 (Box 228, Folder 14)
  - News clippings- Brazil, 1964-1965 (Box 228, Folder 15)
  - News clippings- Canadian Indians, 1965 (Box 228, Folder 16)
  - News clippings- Chile, 1963-1965 (Box 228, Folder 17)
  - News clippings- Colleges, 1964-1965 (Box 228, Folder 18)
  - News clippings- Cornell University, 1964-1965 (Box 228, Folder 19)
  - News clippings- Cuba, 1959-1965 (Box 228, Folder 20)
  - News clippings- Foundations, 1964-1965 (Box 229, Folder 1)
  - News clippings- France, 1964 (Box 229, Folder 2)
  - News clippings- Goldwater, Barry, 1964-1965 (Box 229, Folder 3)
  - News clippings- Guatemala, 1962-1965 (Box 229, Folder 4)
  - News clippings- Mexico, 1964-1965 (Box 229, Folder 5)
  - News clippings- Panama, 1964 (Box 229, Folder 6)
  - News clippings- Venezuela, 1964-1965 (Box 229, Folder 7)
  - Notes, 1954-1979 (Box 229, Folder 8)
  - Notes, 1982-1988 (Box 229, Folder 9)
  - Notes, 1991-1994 (Box 229, Folder 10)
  - Notes, 1995-2001 (Box 229, Folder 11)
  - Notes, undated (Box 229, Folder 12-15)
  - Notes, undated (Box 230, Folder 1-4)
  - Old Spanish trail, undated (Box 230, Folder 5)
  - Oquitoa Mission, undated (Box 230, Folder 6)
  - Pima- Maricopa Confederation documents, 1985-1986 (Box 230, Folder 7)
  - Pinart, undated (Box 230, Folder 8-9)
  - Pitiquito Mission, undated (Box 230, Folder 10)
  - Post-Colombian Native American population trends, 1987 (Box 230, Folder 11)
  - Reference lists, 1999, undated (Box 230, Folder 12)
  - Reyes, Antonio, undated (Box 230, Folder 13)
  - Salazar claims, 1992 (Box 230, Folder 14)
  - Salazar, Jose Francisco and Leonora, undated (Box 230, Folder 15)
  - San Agustin de Tucson, undated (Box 230, Folder 16)
  - School integration crisis in newspapers, 1957 (Box 231, Folder 1)
  - Shivwits Paiute water rights, undated (Box 231, Folder 2-3)
  - Slavery- Fisnado, Mariano, undated (Box 231, Folder 4)
  - Social science citation index, 1969 (Box 231, Folder 5)
  - Social science citation index, 1970-1971 (Box 231, Folder 6)
  - Social science citation index, 1972-1973 (Box 231, Folder 7)
  - Social science citation index, 1974-1975 (Box 231, Folder 8)
  - Social science citation index, 1976-1977 (Box 231, Folder 9)
  - Social science citation index, 1978-1979 (Box 231, Folder 10)
  - Sonora history, undated (Box 231, Folder 11)
  - Sonora population trends, undated (Box 231, Folder 12)
  - Spanish Colonial Tucson, undated (Box 231, Folder 13-14)
  - Tohono O’odham, 1958 (Box 231, Folder 15)
  - Tohono O’odham, 1964-1971 (Box 231, Folder 16)
  - Tohono O’odham, 1964-1971 (Box 232, Folder 1)
  - Tohono O’odham field notes- Robert Thomas, 1953 (Box 232, Folder 2)
  - Tohono O’odham interviews, 1956-1957 (Box 232, Folder 3)
  - Tribal population trends, 1985 (Box 232, Folder 4)
  - Tubac land grants and census, undated (Box 232, Folder 5)
  - Tucson, undated (Box 232, Folder 6)
  - Tucson under Spain, 1971 (Box 232, Folder 7)
  - Tumacocari, undated (Box 232, Folder 8)
  - U.S. Indian relocation policy, 1947-1956 (Box 232, Folder 9)
  - Water use, 1955-1969 (Box 232, Folder 10)
- Series X: Index Cards Files, ca. 1950-2008
  This series includes index cards of research notes, book, newspaper and article citations and research materials such as news clippings about a variety of subjects including Indian tribes such the Tohono O’odham, Hualapai and Gila River Indian Community as well as data cards primarily from research in Peru, Ecuador and Puerto Rico. This series contains restrictions on material in boxes 243-255, 325, 366, 449, 451 and 455.
  - (Box 233)
    News clippings, notes and book citations from 700-1782 concerning the Tohono O’odham, Luis Oacpicagigua and Father Kino.
  - (Box 234)
    News clippings, notes and book citations from 1783-1870 concerning the Tohono O’odham.
  - (Box 235)
    News clippings, notes and book citations from 1871-1905 concerning the Tohono O’odham.
  - (Box 236)
    News clippings, notes and book citations from 1905-1956 concerning the Tohono O’odham.
  - (Box 237)
    News clippings, notes and book citations from 1957-1993 concerning the Tohono O’odham and research in Magdalena (1957).
  - (Box 238)
    News clippings, notes and book citations from 1993- 1998 concerning the Tohono O’odham.
  - (Box 239)
    News clippings, notes and book citations from 1998-2004 concerning the Tohono O’odham, as well as news clippings and notes concerning Camps and Forts in Arizona.
  - (Box 240)
    News clippings, notes and book citations concerning the Tohono O’odham on subjects from Annual cycle to Last Chance Mine Pioneer District.
  - (Box 241)
    News clippings, notes and book citations concerning the Tohono O’odham on subjects from Little Nugget to Yuma Mine and 1000- 1956.
  - (Box 242)
    News clippings, notes and book citations concerning the Tohono O’odham 1957-2003 as well as Gila River news clippings, notes and council minutes and research notes (1952).
  - (Box 243)
    Restricted
  - (Box 244)
  - (Box 245)
  - (Box 246)
  - (Box 247)
  - (Box 248)
  - (Box 249)
  - (Box 250)
  - (Box 251)
  - (Box 252)
  - (Box 253)
  - (Box 254)
  - (Box 255)
  - (Box 256)
    News clippings on epidemics.
  - (Box 257)
  - (Box 258)
  - (Box 259)
    News clippings on epidemics and One Finds Glazed Pottery bibliography.
  - (Box 260)
    Pueblo bibliography and Oneida bibliography.
  - (Box 261)
    News clippings on various Indian tribes.
  - (Box 262)
    News clippings on various Indian tribes including the Pueblo and Apache.
  - (Box 263)
    News clippings on various Indian tribes including the Apache as well as AIDS and Ethnohistory.
  - (Box 264)
    News clippings on AIDS and bibliography of Trade.
  - (Box 265)
    News clippings on various Indian tribes as well as bibliography on historic demography.
  - (Box 266)
    News clippings on festivals and Peru notes.
  - (Box 267)
    News clippings on various Indian tribes as well as a directory of Florida anthropologists.
  - (Box 268)
    News clippings on various Indian tribes and news clippings and notes on Ecuador.
  - (Box 269)
    News clippings on the Akimel O’odham and news clippings and notes on Ecuador.
  - (Box 270)
    News clippings on the Akimel O’odham and a bibliography of Applied Anthropology citations.
  - (Box 271)
    A citation index on Indian tribes.
  - (Box 272)
    News clippings on religious festivals and Fire and Flood as well as invited lectures and notes on Peru.
  - (Box 273)
    Notes from Peru.
  - (Box 274)
    News clippings and notes on Peru.
  - (Box 275)
    News clippings and notes on Peru as well as notes on the festivals of Santa Maria Magdalena Parish, St Francis Xavier and San Francisco del Bac.
  - (Box 276)
    News clippings and notes on Festivals as well as a citation index and notes on Peru.
  - (Box 277)
  - (Box 278)
    News clippings and notes on Peru as well as on Cherokee Indians.
  - (Box 279)
    News clippings on Cherokee and Creek Indians.
  - (Box 280)
    News clippings on Creek and Cocopah Indians.
  - (Box 281)
    News clippings on various Indian tribes including the Havasupai, Seri and Yavapai as well as data for Los Esteros essay.
  - (Box 282)
    News clippings on various Indian tribes including the Mojave, Opata and Tohono O’odham.
  - (Box 283)
    News clippings on various Indian tribes including the Tohono O’odham as well as on garrisons (Tubac).
  - (Box 284)
    News clippings on Tubac.
  - (Box 285)
    News clippings on Tubac as well as Spanish Colonial Frontier research.
  - (Box 286)
    News clippings and citations on Tubac, Spanish Colonial Frontier research and military colonies.
  - (Box 287)
  - (Box 288)
    News clippings on Tubac and Tucson
  - (Box 289)
    News clippings on Tucson.
  - (Box 290)
    News clippings on Tucson as well as Indians bibliography and notes on Vicos, Peru.
  - (Box 291)
    News clippings and notes on Vicos, Peru as well as Pinart.
  - (Box 292)
  - (Box 293)
  - (Box 294)
    News clippings and notes on Peru as well as various Indian tribes including the Paiute and ethnobotony.
  - (Box 295)
    News clippings on various Indian tribes including the Paiute.
  - (Box 296)
  - (Box 297)
  - (Box 298)
    News clippings and notes on Peru (Cornell Peru Project).
  - (Box 299)
  - (Box 300)
  - (Box 301)
  - (Box 302)
  - (Box 303)
  - (Box 304)
  - (Box 305)
  - (Box 306)
  - (Box 307)
  - (Box 308)
  - (Box 309)
  - (Box 310)
  - (Box 311)
  - (Box 312)
  - (Box 313)
  - (Box 314)
  - (Box 315)
  - (Box 316)
  - (Box 317)
  - (Box 318)
  - (Box 319)
  - (Box 320)
  - (Box 321)
  - (Box 322)
  - (Box 323)
  - (Box 324)
  - (Box 325)
  - (Box 326)
  - (Box 327)
  - (Box 328)
  - (Box 329)
  - (Box 330)
  - (Box 331)
  - (Box 332)
  - (Box 333)
  - (Box 334)
  - (Box 335)
  - (Box 336)
  - (Box 337)
    Notes and citations for the Applied Anthropology book.
  - (Box 338)
  - (Box 339)
  - (Box 340)
  - (Box 341)
  - (Box 342)
  - (Box 343)
  - (Box 344)
  - (Box 345)
    News clippings and notes on Peru (Cornell Peru Project) and book citations.
  - (Box 346)
  - (Box 347)
  - (Box 348)
  - (Box 349)
  - (Box 350)
  - (Box 351)
  - (Box 352)
  - (Box 353)
  - (Box 354)
    News clippings and notes on the Gila River Indian Community.
  - (Box 355)
  - (Box 356)
    News clippings and notes on various Indian tribes.
  - (Box 357)
    News clippings and notes on various Indian tribes as well as notes and mailing list for the Indian Tribal Series.
  - (Box 358)
    News clippings and notes on various Indian tribes as well as notes on religious festivals and the Tohono O’odham tribe. (1950-1952)
  - (Box 359)
  - (Box 360)
    News clippings and notes on religious festivals and Indians in Arizona.
  - (Box 361)
    News clippings and notes on overland travel routes and Mexican history documents as well as the Gila River Indian Community.
  - (Box 362)
    News clippings and notes on the Gila River Indian Community as well as Casa Grande.
  - (Box 363)
    News clippings and notes on the Gila River Indian Community as well as Casa Grande and Florence.
  - (Box 364)
    News clippings and notes on the San Carlos Reserve Upper Valleys and the Gila River Indian Community.
  - (Box 365)
    News clippings and notes on epidemics.
  - (Box 366)
  - (Box 367)
    Notes and citations on Dobyns’ Library.
  - (Box 368)
  - (Box 369)
  - (Box 370)
  - (Box 371)
  - (Box 372)
  - (Box 373)
    Notes and citations on Dobyns’ Library. including offprints
  - (Box 374)
  - (Box 375)
  - (Box 376)
  - (Box 377)
  - (Box 378)
  - (Box 379)
  - (Box 380)
  - (Box 381)
  - (Box 382)
    Notes and citations on Dobyns’ Library as well as bibliography of population epidemics.
  - (Box 383)
  - (Box 384)
  - (Box 385)
    Notes and citations on Dobyns’ Library as well as bibliographies.
  - (Box 386)
  - (Box 387)
  - (Box 388)
  - (Box 389)
  - (Box 390)
  - (Box 391)
  - (Box 392)
  - (Box 393)
    Notes and citations on Dobyns’ Library, bibliographies, Native American languages and a Cornell Peru project bibliography.
  - (Box 394)
    Notes and citations on Dobyns’ Library as well as a Cornell Peru project bibliography and address book cards.
  - (Box 395)
    Notes and citations in Human Organization.
  - (Box 396)
  - (Box 397)
    Notes and citations for research proposals,The Navajo People and The Hopi People as well as Latin American bibliographies.
  - (Box 398)
    Notes and citations and offprints.
  - (Box 399)
    News clippings and citations on various Indian tribes and Pinart.
  - (Box 400)